Brian Phillips

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

I am a self-motivated, goal-oriented, hands-on professional, with a successful record of accomplishments. My qualifications consist of project management, web and mobile development using HTML5,CSS3, and multiple Javascript libraries, business management, advertising, marketing, English education, sales, and a few others that are not pertinent. I have years of experience dealing with high level business affairs as well as intercontinental travel. I have written multiple academic papers and currently working on a book about my life and travel experiences. I've started a small development team creating mobile apps and have created multiple websites on my own. I am also knowledgeable in multiple areas of information technology. I continuously educate myself on as many topics as I can. I am very dependable and always follow through with what I say.

SKILLS

- Proficient with frontend technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Sass, jQuery, AngularJS.
- Worked with the Cordova/PhoneGap/Ionic mobile and Electron's desktop development platform.
- Used task-runners such as Bower & Grunt and other tools included in the NPM family.
- Familiar with backend technologies including PHP, Node.JS, Python & Django.
- Knowledgeable in database systems such as MySQL and MongoDB.
- Knowledge in servers systems such as Nginx & Apache.
- Well educated in version control systems such as Git and Docker.
- Have worked closely with CMSystems such as Drupal, Wordpress, & Joomla.
- Well educated in SEO & SEM.
- Familiar with Scrum and Agile methodologies for project management and different task managers such as Asana and Trello.
- Proficient with all office suites, all operating systems (Windows, Linux, Mac) and the mind mapping software called Xmind.
- Proficient in Gimp and Sketch for photo editing and mockups and the recording software called Audacity.

EDUCATION

Associates in Applied Computer Science

Big Bend Community College (2003 – 2005) GPA: 3.6

Bachelors of Science: Information System Security

West Chester University (2006 - 2009) GPA: 3.8

CERTIFICATIONS

- American TESOL Advanced Certification
- American TESOL Children Certification
- American TESOL Business Certification
- American TESOL Expert Certification

LANGUAGES

• I am fluent in English and I have a basic understanding of Spanish and Mandarin Chinese

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Polyphasic Developers Global (8/2016 – Present)

Owner / Lead & Full Stack Developer / Project Manager

I'm the owner of a small software development company. I manage a team of under 10 people at any given time. I'm the project manager and also participate in the development process of each project.

Freelancer Global (1/2015 – 8/2016)

Academic Writer / Developer / English Tutor

I decided to become traveling freelancers. All of my work is done with my computer, via telecommunication. I have been developing web and mobile applications, writing academic papers and doing other side work such as English tuition. I was also involved in the development of a major English app used in China.

Bosch Zhuhai, China (9/2014 – 1/2015)

Adult Business English Teacher

I was responsible for a class of 25 students and educating them with business terminology. I created lesson plans for every class and administered tests on a monthly basis.

Old Suttonian's English Language Centre Zhongshan, China (8/2013 – 8/2014)

ESL Teacher

I was responsible for educating students whose ages ranged from 5 to adults. I used Cambridge and Oxford educational material to create lesson plans and did progress reports for each student. I also managed a student inventory system and was outsourced to other schools for short term classes.

Unipheas.com Global (1/2011 – 12/2013)

Owner

I maintained client portfolios for advertising and marketing campaigns. I helped with the Integration of company networks into the Google Cloud. My specialization was SEO, SEM, social media platforms and analytical data. I also trained employees of clients on how to use Google Apps. The clients ranged from east to west coast of the United States, Ecuador, Taiwan, Fiji Islands, Australia and China.

FPI Management Moses Lake, WA (3/2010 – 09/2011)

Community Director

I managed a 4.2 million dollar apartment complex with ninety-six units and over one hundred residents. I had an office assistant and a maintenance crew of four people. I did budget reports and payroll on a biweekly basis. My tasks included establishing a relationship with distributors and contractors while scheduling monthly or weekly appointments, as well as dealing with anything else that came up.

Columbia Basin Herald Moses Lake, WA (01/2009 – 03/2010)

Advertising Sales Associate

I managed and produced client portfolios for advertisement campaigns. My tasks included setting appointments and scheduling kiosk locations or dates. I had month end reports for all sales or commission and managed incoming subscriptions for customers.

United States Marine Corp. United States (04/2004 – 08/2008)

Aviation Supply Specialist

My duties were to uphold corps values of honor, courage, and commitment. I became a leader of all lower ranking Marines. I have worked with NAV-SUP, military software, and military networks. I was tasked with

distribution of hardware to squadrons and receiving of goods. I also had to uphold a fit physical condition and combat readiness.

Profiles & Portfolio

- https://github.com/unipheas
- https://bitbucket.org/unipheas
- https://hub.docker.com/u/liulanghan/
- http://codepen.io/Unipheas/
- https://mozillians.org/en-US/u/unipheas/
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/unipheas
- https://www.italki.com/teacher/1510498
- http://www.xi-rang.com/
- http://www.dharmabeach.com/
- http://www.healingwithtanya.com/
- http://www.montanitours.com/
- http://ecuador-spanishschool.com/montanita/
- http://www.montanitaspanishschool.com/
- http://www.surffijiislands.com/

WeChat: Unipheas

Skype: liu939dd@outlook.com FaceTime: dp2313265939@icloud.com